Rio! Aishia!
Professor!
I'm so glad. What's going on?
We're not certain of the details yet.
A large number of monsters have appeared
inside or just outside the city.
There are likely to be minotaurs among them.
What will you do?
Since it happened so suddenly,
I don't know the whole situation.
Gathering information is the first priority.
Rio.
If it's me you're worried
about, I'm all right.
I am fully aware that I seem
like your greatest burden,
but if I use magic, I can fight fairly well.
So, um...
Rio, you should take whatever
action you think is best!
I will.
In that case, to ensure that
we can make a move at any time,
the first thing to do is change our clothes.
Yes.
Spirit Chronicles 2
You're magnificent, Master Haruto!
What?
What are you saying?
Sir Haruto, please pay her no mind.
The Battle to Defend Amande
What's that? What's going on?
Look at that!
I heard they spotted monsters!
Have they breached the gate?
That certainly is a lot of monsters.
Still... Amande's response is very fast.
Reinforcements keep arriving.
If things continue like this...
Haruto, I sense that a large number of
monsters have appeared to the east.
The east?
They're coming from the east, too?
Haruto, what do you want to do?
For right now,
can you stay where you are?
Will you stay on standby
with the professor for me?
The residents are evacuating en masse
from the west to the northern districts.
Even if you left right now,
you wouldn't be able to go anywhere.
There will likely be a crush of residents
fleeing from the east very soon.
Staying inside the inn
will be the safest option for now.
What will you do, Haruto?
The defense of the eastern
gate is shorthanded.
I'll go and help hold the monsters off.
Be careful.
Thank you.
I don't intend to let any
monsters get that far, but...
Yes, you can leave Celia to me.
East Gate
Photon Bullet!
There are so many of them.
If reinforcements don't arrive soon...
Photon Bullet!
What?
If it isn't overstepping my bounds,
I'll assist until reinforcements arrive.
Master Haruto!
It's... Miss Chloe, isn't it?
U-Um... Why are you here?
The eastern gate is shorthanded
since it was attacked second,
so I came to lend my support.
Thank you so much!
Then, while we're waiting for
reinforcements to arrive,
let's try to reduce their
numbers as much as we can.
I'll take point. Is that all right?
Y-Yes! If you would!
Then I'll leave the monsters that make
it into the square to all of you.
Understood!
I-Incredible.
He felled that many with just one blow.
What we need right now is information.
No matter how minor it may seem,
report it to us.
Yes, miss.
We've had word from the watchtower
through the magic telecommunicator.
A minotaur and a large number of monsters
have appeared at the east gate.
It seems they've gained entry.
What?
How far in have they gotten?
At the moment, the precise
details are unknown.
They're being held at bay at the entrance
to the plaza inside the east gate.
However, our forces are outnumbered.
I believe we should divert
reinforcements there immediately.
Even if we send soldiers and
adventurers from the rear guard,
we risk them running into the citizens
coming from the other direction.
We dispatched attendants
to the areas near the east gate.
Couldn't we send them there?
We sent the majority of our
people to the west gate.
Currently, we only have Chloe there.
Though, Cosette and a few others
should be in the center of
town directing the evacuation.
Then you should head there immediately.
Collect Cosette and the others on
your way and take them with you.
Understood.
Duke Huguenot's knights
have stayed at the mansion,
so there is no need to worry about me.
Please think only of your duties.
Understood.
Enchant Physical Ability.
Lady Liselotte.
A skilled swordsman has
appeared at the east gate.
He is pushing the monsters back on his own.
Is it Sir Haruto?
Most likely.
It seems I owe him another great debt.
But I'm very grateful.
And Natalie is headed there, too.
I think perhaps the east gate might
have enough of a fighting force now.
To think we'd be able to sneak
in this far. It's too easy!
Please refrain from speaking unnecessarily.
You're no fun.
I'm here at a battle and I'm being
told I have to wait until later.
The least you could do is talk to me.
Then let us speak about work.
As soon as we receive the signal from
the minotaurs, we will take action.
Please make sure that you're
prepared to move at any moment.
Heard and understood.
Now, the aura of that
spirit in human form
has been sitting quietly in the
center of town all this time.
Soon, the defensive forces will
all have moved to the front lines.
Incredible. He's really incredible!
Hey, Chloe, who is that? Who is
that young man fighting over there?
That's Master Haruto!
He saved Lady Liselotte's life and
he's a skilled swordsman!
The word "skilled" doesn't cover all of that!
But even Master Haruto will need to rest.
When he does, we'll be the ones fighting!
Please make sure you're ready for it!
Okay, leave the rear to us!
This is strange.
Why aren't the minotaur or those
humanoid monsters fighting up in front?
With the power those monsters have,
they could push their way
deep into town in an instant.
That minotaur normally wouldn't
hesitate about breaching the gate.
Do they have some other objective?
Aishia, has anything changed in town?
Nothing specific.
Only that people have started
avoiding the plaza near here.
And the evacuation of the residents
should be nearly complete.
Is there any change in
the monsters' movements?
No.
It seems like
they've been able to successfully hold
off the monsters at the west gate.
I see.
Thank you.
I'll talk with the others and see if
it's all right for me to head back.
All right. If anything happens,
I'll contact you immediately.
Right.
Chloe!
Natalie! Cosette!
Um, has there been any damage?
Master Haruto has been fighting alone for us!
I'd expect no less from him.
He's amazing, but...
shouldn't we have him come back now?
He's been out there the
whole time, hasn't he?
He won't be able to sustain his magic.
You're right.
Now that we're here,
we should switch places with him.
Master Haruto!
If I remember rightly,
it's Miss Cosette and...
I am one of Lady Liselotte's
attendants, Natalie.
Master Haruto, we offer you our
deepest thanks for granting us your aid.
Please allow us express our
gratitude on behalf of our lady.
Not at all. Actually, I have a favor to ask.
What is it?
My travel companions are waiting at the inn.
They haven't evacuated yet.
I'd like to go back so
that I can rejoin them.
I see. And that's your favor?
I know it won't really make up for
allowing me to withdraw from here,
but I will take care of that minotaur.
What do you think?
Master Haruto, as you are an ordinary citizen,
we have no reason to keep you here.
And you do realize that it's waiting
all the way in the back, don't you?
It's all right. I can slay it from here.
Y-You can?
I will take care of it now.
I should give it a little more.
And now, if you will excuse me,
I'll take my leave.
Y-Yes! Thank you so much.
You're magnificent, Master Haruto!
What?
Wh-What are you saying?
Sir Haruto, please pay her no mind
and return to your companions.
Right. If you'll excuse me.
West Gate
There are clearly far more monsters here
than when we were attacked in the forest.
I'd like to use extravagant magic to
clear them away in one fell swoop,
but if I'm not careful to ration
my magical energy, I may run dry.
What should I do?
And why aren't they coming
to breach the gate?
It's baffling.
It's a little more dangerous, but my only
choice is to strike further forward.
What is all of this now?
Spirit Chronicles 2
That's the signal.
It's finally our turn, huh?
Let's hurry. The monsters may all be slain
far more quickly than we anticipated.
You're the one our hopes truly lie with.
We're relying on you, young Alphonse.
I know. Leave it to me.
What are they?
All units, do whatever you must to stop them!
I will take care of that hulking beast!
We should go, too. This way.
Haruto!
A monster!
D-Don't come over here!
Mireille, run away!
This is bad!
There are more of them?
Th-Thank you so much!
Not at all. The important
thing is that you're unharmed.
Th-Thank you, mister!
Mother, are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine.
Mother? Mireille?
Wh-What happened here?
We were attacked by monsters and he saved us!
He's really strong!
R-Really? Thank you so much, Master Haruto!
It was nothing. But what brings
you here, Miss Chloe?
W-Well, a few humanoid monsters
managed to make it into the city,
so I was headed to
Lady Liselotte to tell her.
Oh, Chloe!
Rebecca, are you all right?
Hey, young man, thank you! You were amazing!
Oh, um...
I'm very sorry! I'm in a
hurry to deliver a message!
Will all of you hurry and evacuate to the north,
inside the estate walls, for me?
If you talk to the guards at the entrance
to the walls, they should let you in!
I see. Well then, get going, Chloe!
We'll go ahead and evacuate
with this young man here!
Oh, I, um...
Let's go, Haruto.
Cecilia...
All right. Let's do that.
Hey, do monsters always
attack towns this often?
They don't attack frequently,
but it isn't unprecedented.
In the past, towns and villages have
been completely destroyed by monsters.
I see.
Pardon me.
My nerves have made my throat dry.
Estate Wall, North Gate
Now we can feel a little safer.
Thank you, mister.
I didn't do anything much.
All I did was walk with you.
Could it be that you're Master Haruto?
Yes, I am. Why do you ask?
I thought so.
The truth is, we've been told that
if you and your companions arrive,
we're to make it our priority to
show you to the mansion immediately.
It's a direct order from Lady Liselotte.
Oh, I see.
You and your companions
are under our protection.
I realize it's sudden,
but please come this way.
In that case, we'll take you
at your word. Thank you.
Understood.
This way.
It really is a lot easier
when you have a guide.
Those strengthened revenants
can't handle this kind of work.
The guest rooms are down that
way and around the corner.
Got it. Well then, the
rest of this job is yours.
Don't raise a hand to the princess.
And apparently, as long
as you don't kill him,
you're allowed to hurt the Hero if you want.
I know. Leave it to me.
As I am now, I am stronger than a minotaur.
Right.
I can't tell if his intellect
remains, or if it's broken.
Is someone there?
Yes, we're over here.
Who are you?
Oh, I was just taking care of a little
business and now I'm about to leave.
Don't mind me.
Stop!
Show yourself.
Dear, dear.
An adventurer? Are you alone?
You were talking to someone, weren't you?
No, there aren't any other humans here.
Hey. Something just hit the door, didn't it?
Indeed.
Hey, what's going on?
What is that?
M-Monsters?
H-How can they be here?
Next Time
Destined Enemy
"Destined Enemy."
Spirit Chronicles 2
Illustration: Minazuki Futago
I'm Alphonse!